

# **ABOUT ME**

My name Nyonjee Zeogar born and raised in Minneapolis, Mn. I'm a Full Stack Developer with 3+ years of hands on experience designing, developing, and implementing applications and solutions using a range of technologies and programming languages. I am currently seeking to apply my experiences in a challenging role as a Full Stack Developer.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Wordpress Developer Groundworks | Remote

Contract | Sept. 2022 - Mar. 2023

- Developed custom blocks for the WordPress Gutenberg editor to enhance content management and user experience, with a focus on creating a headless CMS for improved flexibility and scalability.
- Successfully migrated the codebase from WP Engine to WPVIP, ensuring a seamless transition and optimization of website performance and security.
- Established a mono repo to integrate a new problem sign step into an existing online booking React app, enhancing the overall functionality and user experience.
- Refactored the online booking React app, initially built using Vanilla js, to incorporate TypeScript for better type safety, code maintainability, and development efficiency.

# Wordpress Developer/ Project Manager Ramsey County Sheriff's Office | St. Paul, MN

Contract | Apr. 2021 - Apr. 2022

- Consulting with internal stakeholders to determine the website's desired appearance and functionalities.
- Conceptualizing the website design process and lead the Wordpress (Divi) development team.
- Developed user-friendly and visually appealing interfaces, and performing SEO procedures.
- Integrating images, embedding videos, and added plugins.
- Troubleshooting and testing prototypes, as well as monitoring the live deployment of the product
- Performed Common Gateway Interface (CGI) and code checks to optimize website performance.
- Provided mentorship to developers using Divi and facilitating suitable interventions to deliver the project on time and within budget.
- Documenting website development processes and procedures.
- Preparing project progress updates for senior executives and performing website demonstrations.





#### **Email**

nyonjeezeogar@gmail.com

# **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Certificate 2019 - 2020

**University of Minnesota College of Continuing & Professional Studies** 

Entrepreneurship and Innovation BS 2023

**Metropolitan State University** 

# SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- Programming Languages:
  - HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript,
     jQuery, Angular JS, ReactJS, JSON,

Node, PHP, Normalize.css, Vanilla.js

- Databases:
  - MongoDB. SQL, and PostgreSQL

# REFERENCE

**Chy Nou Lee** 

**Inspector** 651-248-2488

**Kevin Strange** 

**Groundworks / Scrum Master** 757-576-5386



# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Wordpress Developer NATURALLY WIRED SITEWORKS | St. Cloud, MN

Contract | Nov. 2021 - Jan. 2022

- Built, designed, and maintained all websites and software applications.
- Designed, wrote, and responsible for making edits to website content.
- Understands UI, cross-browser compatibility, and general web functions and standards.
- Creates solutions for identified problems or bugs.
- Communicates with colleagues, managers, and stakeholders daily.
- Executed assignments with the use of web applications, scripts, and programming languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and APIs
- Develops and validates test routines to ensure the quality of the external and internal interface.
- Accomplishes company goals by accepting ownership of new and different requests.

## **Email Developer**

## Applied Knowledge LLC | Maple Grove, MN

Freelance | Sep. 2020 - Apr. 2021

- Worked as project manager/account manager in coordinating and communicating content change requests and production schedule.
- Development of responsive HTML emails and/or landing pages.
- Test email rendering for consistency across all email clients (Gmail, outlook, Mobile, etc.).
- Upload relevant content and set up email campaigns within the email platform.
- Understand and code basic backend API's.
- Develop and update email templates for emails triggered by user and system events.